<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project240z.com - Datsun 240z</title>
    <description>A Datsun project originally prepped for autocross.</description>
    <link>https://www.project240z.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.project240z.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:06:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Passion for Preservation: Chris Hammond&apos;s Role in Historic Preservation Commission</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Not many tech experts have a passion for historic preservation. But &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chrishammond.com&quot;&gt;Chris Hammond&lt;/a&gt; isn’t your typical tech expert. As a Historic Preservation Commission Member in Wildwood City, MO, Chris proves that it’s possible to balance varied interests successfully. You can read more about his unique journey on his personal blog, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chrishammond.com&quot;&gt;ChrisHammond.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 14:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.project240z.com/chris-hammond</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.project240z.com/chris-hammond</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking for another 240z</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking for a Datsun 240z in St. Louis!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re selling a project, be sure to let me know! &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:240z@christoc.com&quot;&gt;240z@christoc.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1973 Datsun 240Z, also known as the Nissan Fairlady Z in Japan, is a classic sports car that gained popularity for its sleek design, impressive performance, and affordability. Here is a summary of the car’s history, design, and production details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;history&quot;&gt;History:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Datsun 240Z was first introduced in 1969 as a 1970 model, marking the beginning of a line of successful sports cars from Datsun, a subsidiary of Nissan. It was designed to appeal to the American market and was influenced by European sports cars of the era. The 240Z quickly gained a reputation for its powerful performance, striking looks, and accessible price point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 240Z showcased a timeless design that combined elements of a classic sports car with a touch of Japanese styling. Its long hood, short rear deck, and low-slung profile gave it a dynamic and aerodynamic appearance. The sleek body featured flowing lines, a prominent grille, and rounded headlights. The interior provided a driver-focused cockpit with comfortable seating, intuitive controls, and sufficient legroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;engine-and-performance&quot;&gt;Engine and Performance:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the hood, the 1973 240Z featured a 2.4-liter inline-six engine, hence the name 240Z, delivering around 151 horsepower and 146 lb-ft of torque. This engine was known for its smooth power delivery and responsiveness. It was paired with a four-speed manual transmission or an optional three-speed automatic. The 240Z boasted impressive acceleration, excellent handling, and a top speed of around 125 mph (201 km/h), making it a thrilling driving experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;production-numbers&quot;&gt;Production Numbers:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During its production run from 1970 to 1973, Datsun manufactured a total of 30,938 240Z cars for the U.S. market. These numbers include all model years, so it is difficult to pinpoint the exact production figures for the 1973 model alone. However, the 240Z’s overall popularity and high demand contributed to its significant production numbers, making it a successful and iconic sports car of its time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1973 Datsun 240Z remains highly regarded by enthusiasts and collectors today for its timeless design, engaging driving experience, and historical significance as one of the pioneers of Japanese sports cars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 14:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.project240z.com/st-louis-240z</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.project240z.com/st-louis-240z</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking for another 240z</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a little while since we&apos;ve owned a Datsun 240z and we&apos;re somewhat ready for another! If you&apos;ve got an old Datsun in the St. Louis Area, or anywhere within a couple hour drive, hit us up, we&apos;re interested in talking to you about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 14:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.project240z.com/looking-for-another-240z</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.project240z.com/looking-for-another-240z</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project240z 10 Years Later</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago today, the 240z took its first, and last, autocross run at Gateway Motorsports Park, in Illinois.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;IMG_3178&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/1099789651/&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3178&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1337/1099789651_2c9cdb1f4a.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poor car didn’t even get to finish it’s first run, blowing a hole in the block before making it across the finish line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;IMG_3214&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/1099962521/in/photostream/&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3214&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1126/1099962521_74ca8f47dc.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lesson learned from the day: Don’t get anxious and compete in a car before it is complete. I hadn’t tuned the car properly, and likely ran it to lean (also didn’t record any of the data, yet again, too anxious). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 years later, we moved the car to Colorado with us, it drove under its own power at that point, but was sold shortly thereafter as we moved again on to the state of California, where we knew we wouldn’t have the resources to keep/maintain the car.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 19:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.project240z.com/project240z-10-years-later</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.project240z.com/project240z-10-years-later</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This 240z gets around</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Apparently that’s the word on the 240z. I sold it in January 2010 (or somewhere close to there) and since then it has apparently changed owners twice (possibly more).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I emailed &lt;a href=&quot;/the-240z-lives-and-it-looks-great&quot;&gt;the guy who sent me photos in October after he painted it&lt;/a&gt;, to see how it was, and he tells me it was sold in December 
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are the new owner, drop me a line, I’m curious how things are going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 17:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.project240z.com/this-240z-gets-around</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.project240z.com/this-240z-gets-around</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 240z Lives! and it looks great!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So it’s been a while since I’ve blogged here on Project240z.com, reason being that I sold the car quite a while ago. Back this summer I got an email from a guy telling me he was the new owner, having purchased it from the guy that I sold it to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, a couple weeks ago I got these in my inbox:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Project240z Lives with a new owner&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17726343@N00/5174189086/&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Project240z Lives with a new owner&quot; src=&quot;http://static.flickr.com/4092/5174189086_52d64c152e.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a title=&quot;Project240z Lives with a new owner&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17726343@N00/5174188330/&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Project240z Lives with a new owner&quot; src=&quot;http://static.flickr.com/4110/5174188330_980c8249fa.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a title=&quot;Project240z Lives with a new owner&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17726343@N00/5173582669/&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Project240z Lives with a new owner&quot; src=&quot;http://static.flickr.com/4090/5173582669_345c4f0614.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a title=&quot;Project240z Lives with a new owner&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17726343@N00/5174187160/&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Project240z Lives with a new owner&quot; src=&quot;http://static.flickr.com/4112/5174187160_abb106c135.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cried a little bit. The car looks great, it has a motor in it, and it even has license plates! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m glad he sent them to be, but it definitely makes me sad, to see the car up and running, all one color, I had it 4 years and never had it looking that good! Great work, I hope to hear more about the car in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still debating what is going on with the 350z, one day I want to trade it and get an EVO or STI, other days I want to keep it and put a turbo on it. We’ll see, for now I imagine it will stick around because we’ve got a lot of other things going on and the budget doesn’t necessarily allow for a turbo AWD right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 01:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.project240z.com/the-240z-lives-and-it-looks-great</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.project240z.com/the-240z-lives-and-it-looks-great</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NorCal UFO Autocross, The Night Before</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it looks like it is finally time to autocross the beast again! It’s been since January. I’m headed to the Northern California United 510 Owner’s club autocross tomorrow in Marina, CA. Hopefully the car holds together and makes it there, runs, and makes it home! I’m curious to see if the leaky exhaust causes me any troubles (sound level, or just w/ people).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m probably going to run in BSP, I don’t think that UFO follows the standard SCCA Classes for 2010, so STR or SSM are out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos and video tomorrow night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.project240z.com/norcal-ufo-autocross-the-night-before</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.project240z.com/norcal-ufo-autocross-the-night-before</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project240z Lives Again</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, it&apos;s true folks, the Project240z lives again! Check out the latest incarnation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Project240z.com&quot; src=&quot;http://sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc4/hs248.snc4/39749_456558199702_685999702_6368642_3742207_n.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;p&gt;So what if it is in a web based video game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 18:24:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.project240z.com/project240z-lives-again</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.project240z.com/project240z-lives-again</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Saying Goodbye</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://mywifeisfaster.blogspot.com/2010/01/saying-goodbye.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;idea blatantly stolen from James Nelson’s Saying Goodbye post&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;CJH_06-05-07-10-02-39 by chrishammond, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/4140330336/&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: inline; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px&quot; alt=&quot;CJH_06-05-07-10-02-39&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2488/4140330336_61e4511b6a_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We’ve been together for almost 4 years, you and I. I was love at first site, but it took a internet chat conversation with 4 guys to get you where I wanted you. Once your previous owner let a price slip I jumped on the opportunity to buy you, and a week later you, and a billion parts, were loaded up into a trailer for the trip home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got you home and you fit right in next to your younger sister, it wasn’t long before she left our family to join Dozzle in Kansas City (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.project350z.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;she’s been recently reincarnated though&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a title=&quot;CJH_06-05-07-15-55-11 by chrishammond, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/4139593465/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;CJH_06-05-07-15-55-11&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2572/4139593465_736007c3d4_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next 6 months you didn’t get much attention, but you did gain an unsightly brother, a 1978 2+2 that you would learn to love later in life, as he provided a replacement heart for you, along with eye sockets and chest plate to cover the heart.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;CJH_06-05-15-18-48-26 by chrishammond, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/4321433512/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;CJH_06-05-15-18-48-26&quot; src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2729/4321433512_984788c373_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;p&gt;In June, about a month after you did start off strong in June by losing your inner self. That was the start of something beautiful, you became an internet star, getting thousands upon thousands of views of your videos. You even show up &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;source=hp&amp;amp;q=240z&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;very high in the search results for 240z&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;350&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/MgUDgNx-sBg&quot;/&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/MgUDgNx-sBg&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It was the spring of 2007 before any real progress was made on you, with the very generous help of many friends you got a new heart. With that new heart you even got to stretch your legs a bit in July and August of that year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;350&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/n2PkfumfCNk&quot;/&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/n2PkfumfCNk&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;IMG_3188 by chrishammond, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/1099837993/&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: inline; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3188&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1152/1099837993_3ca01e4aed_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Before your legs were fully stretched though I decided it would be a good idea to give those legs a go on an autocross course, no video of that day is available, but there are photos of your glorious and fateful run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though you didn’t even get to complete the full run, I had to get out and assist you, and recruit other help as well, to get back to your grid position.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;IMG_3262 by chrishammond, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/1100201961/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;IMG_3262&quot; src=&quot;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1315/1100201961_16bcdff5fe_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Drained by chrishammond, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/1121489208/&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: inline; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px&quot; alt=&quot;Drained&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1107/1121489208_b95723354c_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;You punished me for taking you out for an autocross too early in your recovery, and showed me your displeasure by destroying the number 2 piston, and providing a nice beautiful mix of oil and coolant when I get you home and drained you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this incident you sat for a quite a while, really until late 2008, you lived partially in a warehouse, sometimes in the garage in Missouri. Though with a little effort you got a new heart put in, you even got to cruise around the neighborhood one last time before being loaded onto the trailer and taken to our new home in Colorado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;350&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/pbd7GbTyAiU&quot;/&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/pbd7GbTyAiU&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;@project240z is loaded for trip to colorado. #going2colorado by chrishammond, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/3749868081/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;@project240z is loaded for trip to colorado. #going2colorado&quot; src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2454/3749868081_c4bd798642_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   

&lt;p&gt;Life in Colorado wasn’t as grand as you had hoped though. You did get some attention here and there, but new priorities in life got in the way of the real attention you needed. It was then decided that you would be better served by finding a new owner. Today that new owner came and took you away. I hope you enjoy your new life, you were my first real project car, and while I never completed you, I am greatful for the time we spent together. I will miss you 240z, perhaps one day in the future I may run into one of your twins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.project240z.com/saying-goodbye</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.project240z.com/saying-goodbye</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tis sold</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So this won’t be the final post here on Project240z.com, but we are likely coming close to the end. This weekend the car sold, an airman from the local Air Force base in Denver came by and gave me a deposit for the car. I’m going to try to get the title cleaned up this week and hopefully get it to him this weekend if he comes up with the rest of the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll post again when the car is gone. Thanks for all the interest in the car lately, unfortunately 99% of the interest came after I sold the car, not before, but oh well. For now check out my new toy, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.project350z.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.project350z.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 08:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.project240z.com/tis-sold</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.project240z.com/tis-sold</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
